<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chrislaing.net</title>
    <link>http://chrislaing.net/categories/technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on chrislaing.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://chrislaing.net/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Data Science: not all it&#39;s cracked up to be</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/docker-a-very-simple-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 21:27:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/docker-a-very-simple-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you pay any attention to the technology industry, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that the last few years have seen production hardware become commodotised by public cloud architectures. One can easily rent highly scalable infrastructure from Amazon, Microsoft, Google, and a host of smaller providers. Although these providers have offered an infinite supply - for practical purposes - of virtual machines for some time, the past year has seen a move towards scalable infrastructure on an even more granular level. In particular, this has come in the form of containers and lambda functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lambda functions, probably best exemplified by Amazon&amp;rsquo;s lambda offering, are bare, stateless functions that can be executed in response to events, or explicit calls. They offer amazing utility in certain circumstances, but their usefulness is limited to a subset of cases. In this post, I want to focus more on the former phenomenon: containerisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although containerisation has been around for quite some time, and in several forms, the technology that has really taken off recently is Docker. According to the Docker website,
&amp;gt; Docker containers wrap a piece of software in a complete filesystem that contains everything needed to run: code, runtime, system tools, system libraries – anything that can be installed on a server. This guarantees that the software will always run the same, regardless of its environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>