<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on chrislaing.net</title>
    <link>http://chrislaing.net/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on chrislaing.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chrislaing.net/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Odds and Ends #1</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-1/</guid>
      <description> Spektral is a framework for relational representation learning, built in Python and based on the Keras API. The field of Geometric Deep Learning is starting to get some traction. In particular, doing Deep Learning on graphs presents some interesting possibilities. RPC Frameworks: gRPC vs Thrift vs RPyC for python. The state of Python Packaging. Packing in Python is both improving dramatically and harder than it should be.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybase: Keys for everyone! Part II</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, we discussed Keybase, a clever company that is solving a lot of the classic problems that users have had with PGP: managing keys, verifying identities, trusting third parties, and user experience.
I also mentioned that Keybase insures iteself against an attack on its servers by writing the root of its Merkle tree into the blockchain. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore what this means, and go through the process of verifying this ourselves step-by-step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybase: Keys for everyone! Part I</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Encryption is a topic that has fascinated me for years, less because of its mathematical basis than its applications, both existing and potential. By far my favourite project in this realm is Keybase.
Keybase cleverly solves several major problems with PGP-based encryption technology by taking the attitude that online, your identity is functionally the sum of your online profiles. With Keybase, you can automatically verify that @cjlaing on twitter has a particular key, and can encrypt messages or files for him without having to ascertain and validate his key through some other medium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>