<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chrislaing.net</title>
    <link>http://chrislaing.net/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on chrislaing.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 21:27:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://chrislaing.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Data Science: not all it&#39;s cracked up to be</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/docker-a-very-simple-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 21:27:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/docker-a-very-simple-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you pay any attention to the technology industry, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that the last few years have seen production hardware become commodotised by public cloud architectures. One can easily rent highly scalable infrastructure from Amazon, Microsoft, Google, and a host of smaller providers. Although these providers have offered an infinite supply - for practical purposes - of virtual machines for some time, the past year has seen a move towards scalable infrastructure on an even more granular level. In particular, this has come in the form of containers and lambda functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lambda functions, probably best exemplified by Amazon&amp;rsquo;s lambda offering, are bare, stateless functions that can be executed in response to events, or explicit calls. They offer amazing utility in certain circumstances, but their usefulness is limited to a subset of cases. In this post, I want to focus more on the former phenomenon: containerisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although containerisation has been around for quite some time, and in several forms, the technology that has really taken off recently is Docker. According to the Docker website,
&amp;gt; Docker containers wrap a piece of software in a complete filesystem that contains everything needed to run: code, runtime, system tools, system libraries – anything that can be installed on a server. This guarantees that the software will always run the same, regardless of its environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Hope</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 23:04:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/test-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I had a blog. Being perfectly honest, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a very good blog; it consisted mainly of rants of one kind or another, inane musings, and the occasional photo from my holidays. On the modern web, social media is the default depository for said rants, musings, and photos, and so I had no need of a dedicated space on my website to share them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it occurred to me recently that I now share quite a bit of material relating to my work and academic interests; blog posts, interesting new projects, snippets of code, or more general articles related to science and technology. I distribute these nuggets of enlightenment primarily through closed channels - slack, hangouts, messaging apps - with the sole exception of twitter, depriving my many adoring fans of interesting material, and me of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, my blog is now open again for business, this time with (hopefully) fewer boring political rants, and more interesting links. I hope that you will find it to be of some interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/about/</guid>
      <description>




    
    
        
        
        
        
    

    
    
    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    
        &lt;span class=&#34;image right&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://chrislaing.net/img/about-me/WADING.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matukituki Valley, South island, New Zealand&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;
    



&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a 30 year old data scientist, currently living and working in Bayern, Germany. Born in England, I was raised in New Zealand’s incomparable South Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my spare time, I enjoy hiking, playing and refereeing ice hockey, drinking coffee, weightlifting, computer games, reading blogs, playing guitar, and sampling delicious single malt scotch whisky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working as a Senior Data Scientist in the Global Data &amp;amp; Analytics team of Allianz SE, a global insurance firm headquartered in Munich, and previously worked at Blue Yonder in Karlsruhe.



    
    
        
        
        
        
    

    
    
    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    
        &lt;span class=&#34;image right&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://chrislaing.net/img/about-me/lattice-with-surface.png&#34; alt=&#34;Salvinia-type lattice with fluid surface attached&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;
    


I received my PhD in Applied Mathematics, as well as my undergraduate degrees in Law and Mathematics, from the University of Otago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My doctoral thesis, entitled Numerical Construction of Static Fluid Interfaces with the Embedding Formalism, is an attempt to reformulate the Young-Laplace equation for static fluid interfaces in the language of differential geometry, and to devise a numerical implementation for the system by Finite Elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thesis &lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10523/4878&#34;&gt;is available for download&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Otago OUR Archive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>