<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chrislaing.net</title>
    <link>http://chrislaing.net/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on chrislaing.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://chrislaing.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybase: Keys for everyone! Part I</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


    
    
        
        
        
        
    

    
    
    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    
        &lt;span class=&#34;image right&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://chrislaing.net/img/2016/11/chrislaing_keybase_proof_graph.png&#34; alt=&#34;Graph of Keybase proofs for Keybase user chrislaing&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;
    


Encryption is a topic that has fascinated me for years, less because of its mathematical basis than its applications, both existing and potential. By far my favourite project in this realm is &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keybase cleverly solves several major problems with PGP-based encryption technology by taking the attitude that online, your identity is functionally the sum of your online profiles. With Keybase, you can automatically verify that &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CJLaing&#34;&gt;@cjlaing&lt;/a&gt; on twitter has a particular key, and can encrypt messages or files for him without having to ascertain and validate his key through some other medium. The client software is open source, and works seamlessly with both PGP and NaCl keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the truly excellent features of Keybase&amp;rsquo;s design is its trust model; although their website and file hosting service offers a centralised interface, that interface is entirely orthogonal to the operation of the service. When you want to id someone and verify their key (&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/chrislaing&#34;&gt;me, for example&lt;/a&gt;), the Keybase client goes to each of their listed web identities, finds the proof, and verifies it, without needing to trust the &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io&#34;&gt;keybase.io&lt;/a&gt; website at all. Every time a user verifies someone&amp;rsquo;s identity by tracking them, this proof is written into the blockchain. The entire chain can then be independently verified, without requiring anyone to trust Keybase itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/docs/kbfs&#34;&gt;Keybase filesystem&lt;/a&gt; is an extremely clever extension of the core Keybase concept. What I find most interesting is the idea that, in principle, data can be securely shared with someone who hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet signed up for Keybase, whom you know purely through one of their online identities. When they join Keybase and prove their ownership of that identity, your client will verify the proof and encrypt the file for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keybase is still in an invitation-only testing phase, however they already have over 100,000 users as of the time of writing. The project is bringing a lot of great new ideas together with solid, tried, and tested cryptography, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see where the project goes next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Part II of this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at how to verify Keybase proofs yourself, and traverse a user&amp;rsquo;s cryptographic chain using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Hope</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/a-new-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 23:04:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/a-new-hope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I had a blog. Being perfectly honest, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a very good blog; it consisted mainly of rants of one kind or another, inane musings, and the occasional photo from my holidays. On the modern web, social media is the default depository for said rants, musings, and photos, and so I had no need of a dedicated space on my website to share them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it occurred to me recently that I now share quite a bit of material relating to my work and academic interests; blog posts, interesting new projects, snippets of code, or more general articles related to science and technology. I distribute these nuggets of enlightenment primarily through closed channels - slack, hangouts, messaging apps - with the sole exception of twitter, depriving my many adoring fans of interesting material, and me of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today, my blog is now open again for business, this time with (hopefully) fewer boring political rants, and more interesting links. I hope that you will find it to be of some interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/about/</guid>
      <description>




    
    
        
        
        
        
    

    
    
    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    
        &lt;span class=&#34;image right&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://chrislaing.net/img/about-me/WADING.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matukituki Valley, South island, New Zealand&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;
    



&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a 30 year old data scientist, currently living and working in Bayern, Germany. Born in England, I was raised in New Zealand’s incomparable South Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my spare time, I enjoy hiking, playing and refereeing ice hockey, drinking coffee, weightlifting, computer games, reading blogs, playing guitar, and sampling delicious single malt scotch whisky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working as a Senior Data Scientist in the Global Data &amp;amp; Analytics team of Allianz SE, a global insurance firm headquartered in Munich, and previously worked at Blue Yonder in Karlsruhe.



    
    
        
        
        
        
    

    
    
    

    
    




    
    
        
    


    

    
        &lt;span class=&#34;image right&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;http://chrislaing.net/img/about-me/lattice-with-surface.png&#34; alt=&#34;Salvinia-type lattice with fluid surface attached&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;
    


I received my PhD in Applied Mathematics, as well as my undergraduate degrees in Law and Mathematics, from the University of Otago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My doctoral thesis, entitled Numerical Construction of Static Fluid Interfaces with the Embedding Formalism, is an attempt to reformulate the Young-Laplace equation for static fluid interfaces in the language of differential geometry, and to devise a numerical implementation for the system by Finite Elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thesis &lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10523/4878&#34;&gt;is available for download&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Otago OUR Archive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>