<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chrislaing.net</title>
    <link>http://chrislaing.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on chrislaing.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chrislaing.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Odds and Ends #3</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-3/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered kops, apparently an excellent way to deploy and manage Kubernetes clusters on the cloud. Since managing a k8s cluster seems to be a full-time job at the best of times, I&#39;m interested to see if this really does make it much easier. I have a very mild case of podcast addiction, and am always looking for something great to add to my collection of subscriptions. Nikita Voloboev has published a very interesting list of podcasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odds and Ends #3</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-4/</guid>
      <description>My former colleagues at Blue Yonder (now part of JDA) have introduced Kartothek, software for managing tables stored as parquet files. A great set of documentation on going zero to JupyterHub with Kubernetes. A related piece from Jim Crist on installing JupyterHub on an existing Hadoop cluster. An interesting paper interoducing PATE from a couple of years ago that had passed me by. PATE stands for Private Aggregation of Teacher Ensembles, and is a method for doing semi-supervised transfer learning from private data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odds and Ends #2</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-2/</guid>
      <description>Naftali Tishby on the Information Theory of Deep Learning (embedded below). I&#39;m very enthusiastic about this kind of work, and have resolved to find and read more of it. a16z&#39;s AI Playbook may be a couple of years old now, but it&#39;s still an important read. Traces is a Python library for unevenly-spaced time series analysis. I haven&#39;t had a problem to really try this out on, but the website looks slick 👌🏻.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odds and Ends #1</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/odds-and-ends-1/</guid>
      <description> Spektral is a framework for relational representation learning, built in Python and based on the Keras API. The field of Geometric Deep Learning is starting to get some traction. In particular, doing Deep Learning on graphs presents some interesting possibilities. RPC Frameworks: gRPC vs Thrift vs RPyC for python. The state of Python Packaging. Packing in Python is both improving dramatically and harder than it should be.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybase: Keys for everyone! Part II</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, we discussed Keybase, a clever company that is solving a lot of the classic problems that users have had with PGP: managing keys, verifying identities, trusting third parties, and user experience.
I also mentioned that Keybase insures iteself against an attack on its servers by writing the root of its Merkle tree into the blockchain. In this post, we&#39;ll explore what this means, and go through the process of verifying this ourselves step-by-step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybase: Keys for everyone! Part I</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/keybase-keys-for-everyone-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Encryption is a topic that has fascinated me for years, less because of its mathematical basis than its applications, both existing and potential. By far my favourite project in this realm is Keybase.
Keybase cleverly solves several major problems with PGP-based encryption technology by taking the attitude that online, your identity is functionally the sum of your online profiles. With Keybase, you can automatically verify that @cjlaing on twitter has a particular key, and can encrypt messages or files for him without having to ascertain and validate his key through some other medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Hope</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/a-new-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 23:04:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/a-new-hope/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, I had a blog. Being perfectly honest, it wasn&#39;t a very good blog; it consisted mainly of rants of one kind or another, inane musings, and the occasional photo from my holidays. On the modern web, social media is the default depository for said rants, musings, and photos, and so I had no need of a dedicated space on my website to share them.
However, it occurred to me recently that I now share quite a bit of material relating to my work and academic interests; blog posts, interesting new projects, snippets of code, or more general articles related to science and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I&#39;m Christopher. I live in Wellington, New Zealand, and work in Artificial Intelligence at a global software company.
 I received my PhD in Applied Mathematics, as well as my undergraduate degrees in Law and Mathematics, from the University of Otago.
My doctoral thesis, entitled Numerical Construction of Static Fluid Interfaces with the Embedding Formalism, is an attempt to reformulate the Young-Laplace equation for static fluid interfaces in the language of differential geometry, and to devise a numerical implementation for the system by Finite Elements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>