<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on chrislaing.net</title>
    <link>http://chrislaing.net/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on chrislaing.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chrislaing.net/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the Economics and Ergonomics of LLMs</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/the-economics-and-ergonomics-of-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 10:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/the-economics-and-ergonomics-of-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all the millions of words that have been devoted to the capabilities of LLMs, the economics and ergonomics of these systems seem to me to be under-discussed. In much the same way that technology changes - from records to CDs to streaming - have been a dominant factor in the evolution of popular music, prosaic matters such as cost structures will have a substantial influence on the development and impact of AI. While it is still early days for LLMs, there are already signs that economic factors are impacting everything from product design and technology choice to adoption and even regulation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Large Language Model Iceberg</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/the-large-language-model-iceberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 13:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/the-large-language-model-iceberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the capabilities of Artificial Intelligence (AI) continue to evolve, the term &amp;ldquo;chatbot&amp;rdquo; has become synonymous with a new era of digital interactions. What was once a seemingly futuristic concept is now an integral part of our everyday lives. However, it is the Machine Learning models underlying them - Large Language Models (LLMs) - that are the true powers in these waters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If it&#39;s not mysterious, it&#39;s not AI</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/its-not-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 17:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/its-not-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses are deeply confused about what AI is, and they have every right to be. Differences in terminology have plagued the Data-AI-Software landscape for many years, as anyone who has ever looked for a job as a &amp;ldquo;Data Scientist&amp;rdquo; will attest. Attempts to demystify the topic either conjure a series of analogies that are then strained to breaking point, or try to delve into the actual technology behind the hype, leaving everyone more confused than they were before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will attempt something different: removing the mystery by embracing the mystery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Business Implications of Combinatorial Optimisation by Deep Learning</title>
      <link>http://chrislaing.net/blog/business-implications-of-combinatorial-optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 19:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chrislaing.net/blog/business-implications-of-combinatorial-optimisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Deep Learning has revolutionised a multitude of technical fields, most notably Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing. The implications for business are enormous, with the ramifications of these change still filtering through the mostly technology-shy world of business. There are signs that Combinatorial Optimisation might be the next technical field to undergo Revolution-By-Neural-Network. If this comes to fruition, then the impact on business will be seismic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
